{
  "reference_number": "10662",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "There is enough scientific evidence at hand to know that an ambitious 2050 target is required urgently."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "While Methane and Nitrous Oxide are not as persistent in the atmosphere as Carbon Dioxide, they are 21 and 200-300 times\n (respectively) more effective at trapping heat in our atmosphere. Their effect on warming the climate cannot be ignored, especially\n given that methane and N2O make up more than half our national emissions profile."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "New Zealand should be responsible for its own emissions. This will create carbon offset opportunities within this country, and also\n\n provide greater assurance about the legitimacy of any offsets. Any offsets should be certified to ensure they are legitimate."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I don’t think this should be able to be changed in general as there is too much scope for abuse and watering down the Act. If\n additional more stringent targets become desirable based on further scientific evidence there should be a mechanism for adding\n\n additional targets and considering these when setting carbon budgets but without reducing the original 2050 target of the Act."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This is really important. I worked in the UK under their climate change act and saw first hand the difference this made in ensuring\n business confidence investing in green tech."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "I think it is really important that the carbon budgets sit outside the politics of the day. If budgets are set based on independent\n recommendations by the Climate Change Comission, then we can have confidence that they are appropriate. The only reason to\n change a budget would be to increase the emissions reduction target if scientific evidence showed that earlier budget estimates\n\n were too conservative."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "I think this would destroy business confidence, delaying Investment decisions every election cycle. It’s also unnecessary - new\ngovernments will get to set the next carbon budgets and can build on those already in place."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This is also really important for business confidence. It also helps to establish a policy roadmap that ensures carbon budgets are\nachieved."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "How to best implement policy tools that will effectively generate the required changes in behaviour and create incentives for\n\ninvestment in the green economy, while avoiding any perverse incentives."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "This is a hugely important function of the Climate Change Commission."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The committee should be made up of experts in climate change, science, economics, behavioural science, and business."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    }
  ]
}
